<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>boring-man on yuhe.dev</title>
    <link>https://www.yuhe.dev/tags/boring-man/</link>
    <description>Recent content in boring-man on yuhe.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:34:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.yuhe.dev/tags/boring-man/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rating Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.yuhe.dev/posts/rating-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:34:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuhe.dev/posts/rating-analytics/</guid>
      <description>How do you compare rating algorithms? Or more generally, what is an objective measure of the accuracy of a predictor?
The Motivation I run ratings on a team based shooter called Boring Man, and I&#39;ve always wanted to be able to rank the players in terms of their skills. In fact I believe my first encounters with hobby programming were because of this game.
In previous iterations of my projects, I had always used the Elo rating scheme to adjust player&#39;s ratings, but this time I decided to experiment more and use the TrueSkill rating system by the people at Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discord Bot</title>
      <link>https://www.yuhe.dev/posts/discord-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 10:00:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuhe.dev/posts/discord-bot/</guid>
      <description>Documenting the process of creating a discord bot.
So I wanted a discord bot&amp;hellip; All these times, I have seen people talking about discord bots and using them to do all sorts of amazing things, I have felt left in the dark because the last time I tried using discord.py&#39;s library I failed to wrap my head around everything.
That was a time when my ambitions didn&#39;t measure against my ability to read documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://www.yuhe.dev/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 18:10:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuhe.dev/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog A little about me: I am a person who is interested in statistics and data visualization. I enjoy seeing data represented in interesting ways. Data is beautiful.
I am also very interested in software craftmanship, making high quality code and discovering what are the best design principles.
When you put these two interests together, it is no surprise that I am interested in writing websites that have cool graphs in them!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>